worditout.com 2018-10-01

# Privacy and Cookie Policy – WordItOut

Your privacy is very important to us. That’s why we have considered how to collect only necessary information, protect that data and give you control over it.

This Privacy and Cookie Policy explains these details and more, which applies to any information you provide to us. We encourage you to inform yourself and read this document carefully.

If you’re under 16, make sure you’ve asked an adult (over 18) you trust to have a look at this with you.

## Information we collect

There are 2 types of information that we may collect. Each contains several categories of data which we simply identify here and will discuss in more detail below.

### Personal data

 **Personal data** is any information that could be used (directly or indirectly) to identify you, or any individual.

  * **Account profile** : When you save your User Content, we require your email address.
  * **Correspondence** : Sometimes when you contact us, either communicating by email or using an online contact form, we will receive your email address.
  * **Blacklists** : You may give us your email address to prevent it from being used on the Website.
  * **Online identifiers** : Unique identifiers may be assigned to you for security reasons, usage analysis and sometimes to personalise content.
  * **Technical identifiers** : We automatically receive and save certain types of information whenever you interact with this Website. Examples of personal data we may collect include your IP address; the kind of browser or device you use.

Most of this document refers to your personal data.

### Non-personal data

Any other information we may collect would be non-personal data.

  * **User Content** : When you save or modify word clouds, we collect your User Content. For word clouds, we do not collect the original text used to generate a word cloud.
  * **Customisation** : If you alter a setting on the Website, we may save your preference.
  * **Website usage** : We may collect other information about your online browsing behaviour such as: links you click within the site; date and time of your visit; web pages from which you link to our site; pages you view on our site; your approximate location.

### Personal data in User Content

Please remember that as described in our Terms, you may not put another person’s personal data in your User Content (unless they give you permission). If your personal data is shared in User Content and you have not given permission, please try to contact the person who created the Content or contact us with the form below. You should exercise caution before deciding to disclose voluntarily your own personal data in User Content that can be viewed by the public.

### Children’s data

We do not wish to or knowingly collect or store any personal data from people under the age of 16. If you are under 16, please do not save your word clouds or send your email address to us. Please see how you can protect other personal data below (for example, with private browser settings).

## Why we need your personal data

We only collect personal data when it is necessary, and justify why it is necessary below. If you live in the European Economic Area (EEA), we have identified the lawful basis for processing your personal data ( _Legitimate interest, Legal obligation, Consent_ ).

### Account profile

On saving a word cloud, we require your email address so that we can identify who created the User Content.

  * _Legitimate interest_ : We may have to contact you to provide you with our service and send links in order to to manage your User Content or to notify you that a particular service you use has been changed or suspended.
  * _Legal obligation_ : We may need to contact you if you have violated our Terms or any other law.

### Correspondence

Any personal information you disclose to us through correspondence is needed in order to respond to you about our services.

  * _Legitimate interest_ : We may have to contact you to answer (e.g. a support question) or use your data to find your User Content.
  * _Legal obligation_ : We may need to process this data for legal reasons e.g. if correspondence relates to legal issues.

### Blacklist

If you want us to block your email address from being used on the Website, we need to store it on a blacklist.

  * _Legitimate interest_ : We cannot block your email address if we do not store it. We may block certain email addresses that breach our Terms.

### Online identifiers

Online identifiers may be used to identify whether a visitor to the Website is security threat or not. They may also be used to identify a visitor to compile aggregated Website usage statistics. An identifier may be used to provide you with personalised ads.

  * _Legitimate interest_ : Without such security measures, our Website would be vulnerable to malicious attacks. Usage analytics enable us to correctly manage, maintain and improve the Website.
  * _Consent_ : If you live inside the EEA, your ads will only be personalised with your explicit consent.

### Technical identifiers

We may use technical identifiers to resolve security issues, to troubleshoot technical problems or to analyse Website usage.

  * _Legitimate interest_ : We need this data to continue providing our services in case of any issues or threats.

## Sharing your data

Our Website is designed to never share any of your personal data publicly.

We will not sell, trade or rent personal data to third parties. We do not buy personal data from third parties nor obtain it from publicly accessible sources.

### Trusted third parties

We use a few, trusted third parties to provide, improve, or protect our services. They only have access to the personal data they need to perform these tasks on our behalf. We require that they use your information only for the purposes we’ve authorised and that they protect your personal information to the same standards we do (or better).

The third parties who provide services and may process your personal data are:

  * **Infrastructure** : suppliers include all our web hosting, database storage, email servers and network providers.
  * **Google Analytics** : anonymous, aggregated analysis of how this Website is used.
  * **Advertisers** : Google Adsense helps support this Website so we can provide you services for free.
  * **Widgets** : AddToAny enables you to share content on third party websites.

### Legal reasons

We do reserve the right to share your personal data when we in good faith believe it is necessary for us to do so in order to comply with the law or law enforcement, or to protect the legal rights, property, or the safety of Enideo, you or another individual.

### Business transaction

We may transfer, sell or assign any of the information described in this policy to third parties as a result of a sale, merger, consolidation, change of control, transfer of assets or reorganisation of our business. In this situation, we will continue to ensure the confidentiality of your personal data and give you notice before your personal data is transferred to a third party where this Privacy and Cookie Policy may no longer apply.

### Non-personal data

We may share some of your non-personal data and reserve the right to share personal data that’s aggregated and anonymised in a way that doesn’t identify you.

Some Content is limited-access, where access is gained through an obscured URL system. This obscured URL makes it difficult if not impossible for a third party to guess this URL address. We also monitor and try to block automated requests to such pages, to prevent any unauthorised access. However, because these web pages are not password-protected, a possibility exists that an unauthorised third party could discover them.

You should send or share these links only to people authorised to view such Content. If you are using a shared device, we recommend that you delete your web browsing history.

For the protection of your privacy, we do not put personal data on any such Content.

## Links to other websites

Please note that this Website contains links to other websites. You should carefully review the privacy policies of those sites; they may differ from this document. We have no control over and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for the content, privacy policies or practices of such third party websites.

## Keeping your data secure

We are committed to protecting personal data. We keep your personal data secure by following industry-standard technical and organisational practices. However, please note that no system is ever completely secure and we cannot guarantee this. By using our Website, you accept the inherent risks of providing information online.

## Countries your data may enter

Personal data may be transferred to and processed in a country outside of your own, ours (the United Kingdom) or the EEA. In such instances we will use appropriate safeguards to ensure that your personal data is treated securely and in accordance with this policy and applicable legislation.

## How long we keep your personal data

We will only hold your personal data for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this policy or for legal reasons (as required or permitted by law). Even if we remove your personal data it may persist on back-up or archival media for a longer period.

Please note that details on how to change or remove your data are given below.

## How you can manage your data

Some of your data can be managed by yourself. For anything else please contact us by email using the contact form below or by post to our address.

### Account profile and User Content

You do not have to save a word cloud and give us your email address. If you do, you can remove all your Account profile data and User Content at any time with the Secret Link provided to you by email. That page also allows you to access and manage some of this data.

### Online identifiers

Online identifiers can be blocked or removed with your browser settings. More details about cookies and similar technologies can be found below.

### Any other personal data

As described with your rights below, you can contact us if you wish to access, update or remove your personal data, such as your email address.

## Cookies and similar technologies

Like many websites, we may store data on your browser or device using cookies or similar web technologies. Cookies are small plain text files that can be saved on your device or browser. Similar web technologies include browser web storage, web beacons and application data caches. As an example, the type of information that might be stored in a cookie could be a randomly assigned identification number. This example would be an Online identifier.

These may be used by us and our trusted third parties to save your setting preferences, to compile usage statistics, to target advertisements or to optimise the Website.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/). To find information relating to other browsers, visit the browser’s website.

If you reject cookies and similar technologies by changing your browser settings then be aware that this may disable some of the functionality of this Website.

Although we have selected which third parties provide us services, Enideo has no direct access nor control as to third party practices (including which cookies they use, if any) and it is suggested that you read their privacy policies separately.

  * Advertisers & Analytics: [Google](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).
  * Infrastructure: [Cloudflare](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/); [Layershift](https://www.layershift.com/legal/).
  * Widgets: [AddToAny](https://www.addtoany.com/privacy).

## Your rights

If you are an individual living in the EEA, you have certain rights over your personal data. These rights may also be extended to other individuals globally.

Some of these rights can be enforced yourself by managing your data as described above.

In addition, you can discuss or apply your rights by contacting us by email using the contact form below or by post to our address (also given below). We may confirm your request or require proof of your identification. We aim to comply within 28 days of receipt of your request.

Whilst most requests will be handled for free, we may charge a reasonable administration fee in some circumstances as permitted by law.

### Access your data

You have the right to confirmation that we are processing your personal data, a copy of your personal data and details on how we process your personal data.

### Rectify your data

You can request that we update your personal data if it is inaccurate or incomplete. For example, we can update your email address if you can prove that you own the existing one.

### Restrict your data

You have the right to limit the way that we use your personal data.

### Erase your data

You can request that we remove your personal data, unless we are required to retain it for a _Legal obligation_. Remember you can remove your Account profile from your Secret Link.

### Portable data

You can obtain a copy your personal data in a structured, machine-readable format to reuse for your own purposes across different services, unless it is only processed for a _Legal obligation_ or _Legitimate interest_.

### Withdrawing consent

Where you have given us _Consent_ to collect and use your data, you can always freely withdraw your consent. This is often in the same way as you gave it to us, or by contacting us as previously explained in this section. You might do this if you want to be removed from a Blacklist or from a marketing list.

### Objecting with us

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data. You do not have this right if we process your data under _Consent_ , but in that case you do have the right to withdraw your consent. Your right to object may also not apply if the processing is for certain _Legal obligations_. It does include the right to object to any direct marketing.

### Complaining to an authority

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority. We would ask that you contact us directly first. If you’re not satisfied with the way we handle any complaint you make in relation to your personal data then you could refer your complaint to the relevant data protection regulator. In the UK, this is the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, SK9 5AF.

## Contact us

If you want to request information about our Privacy and Cookie Policy, you can write to the data controller Enideo Ltd by email using the contact form below or by post to: 206 Charlton Road, Kingswood, Bristol, BS15 1LY, UK.

## Changes

If we make changes to this policy we will post the updated policy on this Website noting the effective date of any updates. If such an update includes different purposes for using your personal data, we will promptly provide you notice of any such changes (and, where necessary, obtain Consent).

This Privacy and Cookie Policy is incorporated in this Website’s Terms of Use.

This document was last updated on the 29 May 2018.

Contact us
